Benjamin Smith Barton Papers 1789-1815 Mss.B.B284d
American Philosophical Society
- Series IV. Graphic materials, 1773-ca.1815; 2 boxes; 0.75 linear feet
  - Spigelia marylandica L., 1 watercolor; Turpin, Pierre Jean François (Othertype OS)
  - Theaceous genus not placed., n.d.; 1 watercolor and ink drawing; Turpin, Pierre Jean François (Othertype OS)
  - Trillium grandiflorum (Michx.), and proof., 1 watercolor. 1 proof; Turpin, Pierre Jean François (Othertype OS)
  - Trillium undulatum Willd., 1 watercolor; Turpin, Pierre Jean François (Othertype OS)
  - Vincetoxicum gonocarpos Walt., n.d.; 1 watercolor; Turpin, Pierre Jean François (Othertype OS)
    Also flower dissection of Crassa virginiana L. ?
  - Viola hastata Michx.?, n.d.; 1 watercolor; Turpin, Pierre Jean François (Othertype OS)
  - Tussilago alpina, 1789; 1 engraving
    Colored print from botanical magazine, pl. 84.
  - Ulva? Conferva rhizodes. No. 2, n.d.; 1 item
  - Unknown. "Tome III, Tab. XXXII." Plate. No identification., n.d.; 1 engraving (Othertype OS)
  - Utricularia vulgaris L. [Greater bladderwort]., n.d.; 1 watercolor (Othertype OS)
  - Zak-rot, ou Rat de Suriname. Phalanger [reidentification: upper image appears to be a marsupial rather than a rodent], n.d.; 1 engraving
    Also includes "Crapaud a pattes de Canard" (toad with webbed Feet). Plate. Tome XXI
- Series V. Printing Plates
  Copper plates for illustrations used for Barton's Elements of Botany, 1815, and other publications.
  - Ancient Remains, n.d.; 1 item
  - Alligator or Hell Binder [Salamander?], 2-3; 2 items; Barton, Benjamin Smith, 1766-1815
  - Arms and legs of various animals, 1; 1 item; Barton, Benjamin Smith, 1766-1815
  - Flower, n.d.; 4-6; 3 items; Bartram, William
  - Bird/Flower, n.d.; 14; 1 item; an etching on each side
  - Dog, n.d.; 15; 1 item
  - Duck's head, n.d.; 16; 1 item
  - Fish, n.d.; 7; 1 item
    Profile of fish. "JB Keim" stamped on back.
  - Flower and leaf, 13; 1 item
  - Flower, n.d.; 8-12; 5 items
  - Fossil teeth, n.d.; 17-18; 2 items
  - Head of a man (Native American), n.d.; 20; 1 item
  - Heart, 1786; 19; 1 item
  - Human skull, n.d.; 21; 1 item
  - Indian head, 22; 1 item
  - Linnean Society of London, 1788; 1 item
  - Magnolia, n.d.; 23; 1 item
  - Map, n.d.; 24; 1 item
  - Mole, n.d.; 25-26; 2 items
  - Opossum (baby), n.d.; 27; 1 item
  - Plant, n.d.; 28; 1 item
  - Porpoise, n.d.; 29; 1 item
  - Sarracenia Calceolata, n.d.; 1 item
  - Shahaka, Mandan Chief, 30; 1 item
  - Skulls (mole, boar, mastadon, etc.), n.d.; 31; 1 item
  - Flower, n.d.; 32-34; 3 items; Turpin, Pierre Jean François
  - Virginia-Spider-wort, n.d.; 35; 1 item
  - Blank plates, 36-42; 7 items